export const chapter9StudyData = [
  // Key Terms
  {
    id: "KT901",
    front: "accommodation",
    back: "adjustment of a schema by changing a scheme to accommodate new information different from what was already known"
  },
  {
    id: "KT902",
    front: "adolescence",
    back: "period of development that begins at puberty and ends at early adulthood"
  },
  {
    id: "KT903",
    front: "adrenarche",
    back: "maturing of the adrenal glands"
  },
  {
    id: "KT904",
    front: "assimilation",
    back: "adjustment of a schema by adding information similar to what is already known"
  },
  {
    id: "KT905",
    front: "attachment",
    back: "long-standing connection or bond with others"
  },
  {
    id: "KT906",
    front: "authoritarian parenting style",
    back: "parents place a high value on conformity and obedience, are often rigid, and express little warmth to the child"
  },
  {
    id: "KT907",
    front: "authoritative parenting style",
    back: "parents give children reasonable demands and consistent limits, express warmth and affection, and listen to the child's point of view"
  },
  {
    id: "KT908",
    front: "avoidant attachment",
    back: "characterized by child's unresponsiveness to parent, does not use the parent as a secure base, and does not care if parent leaves"
  },
  {
    id: "KT909",
    front: "cognitive development",
    back: "domain of lifespan development that examines learning, attention, memory, language, thinking, reasoning, and creativity"
  },
  {
    id: "KT910",
    front: "cognitive empathy",
    back: "ability to take the perspective of others and to feel concern for others"
  },
  {
    id: "KT911",
    front: "conception",
    back: "when a sperm fertilizes an egg and forms a zygote"
  },
  {
    id: "KT912",
    front: "concrete operational stage",
    back: "third stage in Piaget's theory of cognitive development; from about 7 to 11 years old, children can think logically about real (concrete) events"
  },
  {
    id: "KT913",
    front: "conservation",
    back: "idea that even if you change the appearance of something, it is still equal in size, volume, or number as long as nothing is added or removed"
  },
  {
    id: "KT914",
    front: "continuous development",
    back: "view that development is a cumulative process: gradually improving on existing skills"
  },
  {
    id: "KT915",
    front: "critical (sensitive) period",
    back: "time during fetal growth when specific parts or organs develop"
  },
  {
    id: "KT916",
    front: "developmental milestone",
    back: "approximate ages at which children reach specific normative events"
  },
  {
    id: "KT917",
    front: "discontinuous development",
    back: "view that development takes place in unique stages, which happen at specific times or ages"
  },
  {
    id: "KT918",
    front: "disorganized attachment",
    back: "characterized by the child's odd behavior when faced with the parent; type of attachment seen most often with kids that are abused"
  },
  {
    id: "KT919",
    front: "egocentrism",
    back: "preoperational child's difficulty in taking the perspective of others"
  },
  {
    id: "KT920",
    front: "embryo",
    back: "multi-cellular organism in its early stages of development"
  },
  {
    id: "KT921",
    front: "emerging adulthood",
    back: "newly defined period of lifespan development from 18 years old to the mid-20s; young people are taking longer to complete college, get a job, get married, and start a family"
  },
  {
    id: "KT922",
    front: "fine motor skills",
    back: "use of muscles in fingers, toes, and eyes to coordinate small actions"
  },
  {
    id: "KT923",
    front: "formal operational stage",
    back: "final stage in Piaget's theory of cognitive development; from age 11 and up, children are able to deal with abstract ideas and hypothetical situations"
  },
  {
    id: "KT924",
    front: "gonadarche",
    back: "maturing of the sex glands"
  },
  {
    id: "KT925",
    front: "gross motor skills",
    back: "use of large muscle groups to control arms and legs for large body movements"
  },
  {
    id: "KT926",
    front: "hospice",
    back: "service that provides a death with dignity; pain management in a humane and comfortable environment; usually outside of a hospital setting"
  },
  {
    id: "KT927",
    front: "menarche",
    back: "beginning of menstrual period; around 12-13 years old"
  },
  {
    id: "KT928",
    front: "mitosis",
    back: "process of cell division"
  },
  {
    id: "KT929",
    front: "motor skills",
    back: "ability to move our body and manipulate objects"
  },
  {
    id: "KT930",
    front: "nature",
    back: "genes and biology"
  },
  {
    id: "KT931",
    front: "newborn reflexes",
    back: "inborn automatic response to a particular form of stimulation that all healthy babies are born with"
  },
  {
    id: "KT932",
    front: "normative approach",
    back: "study of development using norms, or average ages, when most children reach specific developmental milestones"
  },
  {
    id: "KT933",
    front: "nurture",
    back: "environment and culture"
  },
  {
    id: "KT934",
    front: "object permanence",
    back: "idea that even if something is out of sight, it still exists"
  },
  {
    id: "KT935",
    front: "permissive parenting style",
    back: "parents make few demands and rarely use punishment"
  },
  {
    id: "KT936",
    front: "physical development",
    back: "domain of lifespan development that examines growth and changes in the body and brain, the senses, motor skills, and health and wellness"
  },
  {
    id: "KT937",
    front: "placenta",
    back: "structure connected to the uterus that provides nourishment and oxygen to the developing baby"
  },
  {
    id: "KT938",
    front: "prenatal care",
    back: "medical care during pregnancy that monitors the health of both the mother and the fetus"
  },
  {
    id: "KT939",
    front: "preoperational stage",
    back: "second stage in Piaget's theory of cognitive development; from ages 2 to 7, children learn to use symbols and language but do not understand mental operations and often think illogically"
  },
  {
    id: "KT940",
    front: "primary sexual characteristics",
    back: "organs specifically needed for reproduction"
  },
  {
    id: "KT941",
    front: "psychosexual development",
    back: "process proposed by Freud in which pleasure-seeking urges focus on different erogenous zones of the body as humans move through five stages of life"
  },
  {
    id: "KT942",
    front: "psychosocial development",
    back: "process proposed by Erikson in which social tasks are mastered as humans move through eight stages of life from infancy to adulthood"
  },
  {
    id: "KT943",
    front: "resistant attachment",
    back: "characterized by the child's tendency to show clingy behavior and rejection of the parent when she attempts to interact with the child"
  },
  {
    id: "KT944",
    front: "reversibility",
    back: "principle that objects can be changed, but then returned back to their original form or condition"
  },
  {
    id: "KT945",
    front: "schema (plural = schemata)",
    back: "concept (mental model) that is used to help us categorize and interpret information"
  },
  {
    id: "KT946",
    front: "secondary sexual characteristics",
    back: "physical signs of sexual maturation that do not directly involve sex organs"
  },
  {
    id: "KT947",
    front: "secure attachment",
    back: "characterized by the child using the parent as a secure base from which to explore"
  },
  {
    id: "KT948",
    front: "secure base",
    back: "parental presence that gives the infant/toddler a sense of safety as he explores his surroundings"
  },
  {
    id: "KT949",
    front: "sensorimotor stage",
    back: "first stage in Piaget's theory of cognitive development; from birth through age 2, a child learns about the world through senses and motor behavior"
  },
  {
    id: "KT950",
    front: "socioemotional selectivity theory",
    back: "social support/friendships dwindle in number, but remain as close, if not more close than in earlier years"
  },
  {
    id: "KT951",
    front: "spermarche",
    back: "first male ejaculation"
  },
  {
    id: "KT952",
    front: "stage of moral reasoning",
    back: "process proposed by Kohlberg; humans move through three stages of moral development"
  },
  {
    id: "KT953",
    front: "temperament",
    back: "innate traits that influence how one thinks, behaves, and reacts with the environment"
  },
  {
    id: "KT954",
    front: "teratogen",
    back: "biological, chemical, or physical environmental agent that causes damage to the developing embryo or fetus"
  },
  {
    id: "KT955",
    front: "uninvolved parenting style",
    back: "parents are indifferent, uninvolved, and sometimes referred to as neglectful; they don't respond to the child's needs and make relatively few demands"
  },
  {
    id: "KT956",
    front: "zygote",
    back: "structure created when a sperm and egg merge at conception; begins as a single cell and rapidly divides to form the embryo and placenta"
  },
  // Review Questions
  {
    id: "R901",
    front: "The view that development is a cumulative process, gradually adding to the same type of skills is known as ________.",
    back: "continuous development"
  },
  {
    id: "R902",
    front: "Developmental psychologists study human growth and development across three domains. Which of the following is not one of these domains?",
    back: "psychological"
  },
  {
    id: "R903",
    front: "How is lifespan development defined?",
    back: "The study of how we grow and change from conception to death."
  },
  {
    id: "R904",
    front: "The idea that even if something is out of sight, it still exists is called ________.",
    back: "object permanence"
  },
  {
    id: "R905",
    front: "Which theorist proposed that moral thinking proceeds through a series of stages?",
    back: "Lawrence Kohlberg"
  },
  {
    id: "R906",
    front: "According to Erikson's theory of psychosocial development, what is the main task of the adolescent?",
    back: "forming an identity"
  },
  {
    id: "R907",
    front: "Which of the following is the correct order of prenatal development?",
    back: "zygote, embryo, fetus"
  },
  {
    id: "R908",
    front: "The time during fetal growth when specific parts or organs develop is known as ________.",
    back: "critical period"
  },
  {
    id: "R909",
    front: "What begins as a single-cell structure that is created when a sperm and egg merge at conception?",
    back: "zygote"
  },
  {
    id: "R910",
    front: "Using scissors to cut out paper shapes is an example of ________.",
    back: "fine motor skills"
  },
  {
    id: "R911",
    front: "The child uses the parent as a base from which to explore her world in which attachment style?",
    back: "secure"
  },
  {
    id: "R912",
    front: "The frontal lobes become fully developed ________.",
    back: "by 25 years old"
  },
  {
    id: "R913",
    front: "Who created the very first modern hospice?",
    back: "Cicely Saunders"
  },
  {
    id: "R914",
    front: "Which of the following is the order of stages in KÃ¼bler-Ross's five-stage model of grief?",
    back: "denial, anger, bargaining, depression, acceptance"
  }
];

export default chapter9StudyData;
